Guide to the H. G. Merriam Papers 1890-1980
Maureen and Mike Mansfield Library, The University of Montana--Missoula
- Writings, 1902-1980; Series VIII; 5.5 linear feet
  - Uniting Social Studies and Language Programs Through Regional Materials-manuscript, 1947 (Box-folder 28/15)
  - Story collection from Frontier and Midland for Possible book, (We Are All Human), 1947 (Box-folder 28/16)
  - Story collection from Frontier and Midland for Possible book, (We Are All Human), 1947 (Box-folder 28/17)
  - Of So Much Worth-presentation, 1947-05-14 (Box-folder 29/1)
  - Understanding Great Men-presentation to Women's Club, 1947-10-14 (Box-folder 29/2)
  - Who Can Teach Creative Writing, 1947-11 (Box-folder 29/3)
  - A Note on the Humanities in Higher Education-correspondence and manuscript, 1948 (Box-folder 29/4)
  - Does the Northwest Believe in Itself?-presentation, 1948 (Box-folder 29/5)
  - Pacific Northwest Conference on the Arts and Sciences, 1948-04 (Box-folder 29/6)
  - Commencement Address-Rocky Mountain College, 1949 (Box-folder 29/7)
  - Every Graduate an Educated Person-presentation, 1950 (Box-folder 29/8)
  - Northwest Literature, What is it and Why-presentation, 1950 (Box-folder 29/9)
  - Short Stories manuscript for Writer's Conference, 1952 (Box-folder 29/10)
  - Montana Writing-correspondence, 1954-1958 (Box-folder 29/11)
  - Montana Writing-manuscript, undated (Box-folder 29/12)
  - Cosmos Club Presentation-notes and articles on architecture, 1959 (Box-folder 29/13)
  - James R. Thomas, 1884-1959, 1959 (Box-folder 29/14)
  - Frontier Omnibus, 1959 (Box-folder 29/15)
  - Frontier Literature Lecture-notes, 1960s (Box-folder 29/16)
  - Western Classics -presentation, 1960 (Box-folder 29/17)
  - Communication in a Space Age-speech at Northern Montana College, 1961 (Box-folder 29/18)
  - Reading, Northern-presentation, 1962 (Box-folder 29/19)
  - Librarians, Books, Readers and Reading-manuscript, 1963 (Box-folder 29/20)
  - Missoula County History-manuscripts (1), 1964 (Box-folder 29/21)
  - Missoula County History-research and notes (2), 1947-1964 (Box-folder 29/22)
  - Missoula County History-research, notes, and correspondence (3), 1964-1968 (Box-folder 29/23)
  - Folklore-correspondence and notes, 1965-1968 (Box-folder 29/24)
  - Ronan-notes and correspondence, 1965-1973 (Box-folder 30/1)
  - Ronan-manuscript edited by H.G. Merriam-preface to Chap. VI (1), 1932 (Box-folder 30/2)
  - Ronan-Chap. VII to Appendix B (2), 1932 (Box-folder 30/3)
  - Way Out West-correspondence, 1966-1967 (Box-folder 30/4)
  - Way Out West-correspondence, 1968-1970 (Box-folder 30/5)
  - Way Out West-correspondence, 1970's (Box-folder 30/6)
  - Way Out West-publisher's contract, 1967 (Box-folder 30/7)
  - Way Out West-contents and notes, undated (Box-folder 30/8)
  - Way Out West-book reviews, 1970-1971 (Box-folder 30/90)
  - Article on Frank Bird Linderman-correspondence, 1962 (Box-folder 30/10)
  - Recollections of Charley Russell-correspondence, 1962-1964 (Box-folder 30/11)
  - Recollections of Charley Russell-correspondence with the Linderman family, 1962-1964 (Box-folder 30/12)
  - Recollections of Charley Russell, sales and royalty statements, 1963-1968 (Box-folder 30/13)
  - Recollections of Charley Russell, reprint correspondence, 1979-1980 (Box-folder 30/14)
  - Recollections of Charley Russell, publicity and reviews, 1963-1964 (Box-folder 30/15)
  - University of Oklahoma Press, 1965-1976 (Box-folder 31/1)
  - Montana Adventure-correspondence, 1964 (Box-folder 31/2)
  - Montana Adventure-correspondence, 1965 (Box-folder 31/3)
  - Montana Adventure-correspondence, 1966 (Box-folder 31/4)
  - Montana Adventure-correspondence, 1967 (Box-folder 31/5)
  - Montana Adventure-correspondence, 1968-1969 (Box-folder 31/6)
  - Montana Adventure-memorandum of agreement, 1965 and 1967 (Box-folder 31/7)
  - Montana Adventure-research notes, undated (Box-folder 31/8)
  - Montana Adventure-book reviews, 1968-1969 (Box-folder 31/9)
  - U.M. History-Introduction (Box-folder 31/10)
  - U.M. History-Craig Years (Box-folder 31/11)
  - U.M. History-Duniway Years (Box-folder 31/12)
  - U.M. History-Craighead Years (Box-folder 31/13)
  - U.M. History-Elliott Years, 1915-1917 (Box-folder 31/14)
  - U.M. History-Sisson Years, 1917-1921 (Box-folder 31/15)
  - U.M. History-Clapp Years, 1921-1935 (Box-folder 31/16)
  - U.M. History-Simmons Years, 1936-1940 (Box-folder 32/1)
  - UM. History-Melby Years, 1943-1944 (Box-folder 32/2)
  - U.M. History-McCain Years, 1945-1950 (Box-folder 32/3)
  - U.M. History-Mc Farland Years (1), 1951-1958 (Box-folder 32/4)
  - U.M. History-Mc Farland Years (2), 1951-1958 (Box-folder 32/5)
  - U.M. History-Gordon Castle (Box-folder 32/6)
  - U.M. History-Newburn Years, 1959-1963 (Box-folder 32/7)
  - U.M. History-Johns Years, 1963-1966 (Box-folder 32/8)
  - U.M. History-Pantzer Years (1), 1966- (Box-folder 32/9)
  - U.M. History-Pantzer Years (2), 1966- (Box-folder 32/10)
  - U.M. History-Interchapters (Box-folder 33/1)
  - U.M. History-Manuscript (1) (Box-folder 33/2)
  - U.M. History-Manuscript (2) (Box-folder 33/3)
  - U.M. History-Research (1) (Box-folder 33/4)
  - U.M. History-Research (2) (Box-folder 33/5)
  - U.M. History-dates (Box-folder 33/6)
  - U.M. History-correspondence and newspaper clippings, 1968-1971 (Box-folder 33/7)
  - The University of Montana, A History-copy of book, 1970 (Box-folder 33/8)
  - Ho! For the West-correspondence and notes, 1973-1976 (Box-folder 34/1)
  - Ho! For the West-research negatives, undated (Box-folder 34/2)
  - Ho! For the West-book prints, undated (Box-folder 34/3)
  - Ho! For the West-partial manuscript (unpublished), undated (Box-folder 34/4)
  - Ho! For the West-partial manuscript (unpublished), undated (Box-folder 34/5)
  - Ho! For the West-manuscript (unpublished), undated (Box-folder 34/6)
  - Ho! For the West-manuscript (unpublished), undated (Box-folder 34/7)
  - Ho! For the West-manuscript (unpublished), undated (Box-folder 34/8)
  - Ho! For the West-manuscript (unpublished), undated (Box-folder 34/9)
  - Ho! For the West-manuscript (unpublished), undated (Box-folder 34/10)
  - Commencement Address-College of Arts and Sciences-U.M., 1972 (Box-folder 34/11)
  - Twenty Best Books of Montana-information and correspondence, 1972-1977 (Box-folder 34/12)
  - Twenty Best Books of Montana-information and correspondence, 1972-1977 (Box-folder 34/13)
  - Cosmos Club Papers and Notes, 1976 (Box-folder 35/1)
  - The Long Friendship-correspondence, 1977-1980 (Box-folder 35/2)
  - The Long Friendship-copyright information, 1979 (Box-folder 35/3)
  - The Long Friendship-copies of Linderman-Russell letters, 1914-1919 (Box-folder 35/4)
  - The Long Friendship-manuscripts, undated (Box-folder 35/5)
  - The Golden Valley-research materials, 1977 (Box-folder 35/6)
  - The Golden Valley -manuscripts, undated (Box-folder 35/7)
  - The Golden Valley-correspondence and book reviews, 1977-1978 (Box-folder 35/8)
  - Difficulties at the University of Montana-KUFM radio broadcast, 1978-04-22 (Box-folder 35/9)
  - Article for American Oxonian-correspondence and manuscript, 1978 (Box-folder 35/10)
  - Notecards, Writing Research Notes (Box-folder File box/36)
- Writings of Others, 1926-1970; Series IX; 13 folders
  This series includes correspondence and published materials gathered by Merriam out of personal interest or submitted to Merriam both as gifts and as requests for editorial feedback. This series contains extensive correspondence and a portion of text material regarding The Galloping Swede, by Hugo Aronson and Lou O. Brockman. Merriam provided extensive editorial advice on the manuscript through his correspondence with Brockman and extended assistance in contacting potential publishers. Merriam's involvement with the manuscript remained informal throughout the project and received only a note of acknowledgement in the published volume.
  Materials are arranged alphabetically by author.
  - Baldwin, Grace Davidson-poem, undated (Box-folder 35/11)
  - Brockman, Lou O., The Galloping Swede, Correspondence, 1967-1970 (Box-folder 35/12)
  - Brockman, Lou O., The Galloping Swede, Text Materials, undated (Box-folder 35/13)
  - Fishwick, Marshall, "The Twist: Brave New Whirl", 1962 (Box-folder 35/14)
  - Jones, Jenkin Lloyd, "Who Is Tampering with the Soul of America", 1961 (Box-folder 35/15)
  - King, Walter-article, 1962 (Box-folder 35/16)
  - Lewis, C. Day-article "Of a Poem", undated (Box-folder 35/17)
  - McCoy, E.-Bibliography of Negro Literature, 1926-1928, undated (Box-folder 35/18)
  - Moss, Honorable Frank E.-Congressional Testimony "Letter from the West", 1960 (Box-folder 35/19)
  - Saturday Review-issue on photography in the fine arts, 1959-05-16 (Box-folder 35/20)
  - Stegner, Wallace "The West Coast: Region with a View", 1959 (Box-folder 35/21)
  - Unknown student-poem, undated (Box-folder 35/22)
  - Venn, George-Critique of Four Pacific Northwest Novels, undated (Box-folder 35/23)
- Awards and Honors, 1920-1975; Series X; 0.25 linear feet
  This series includes awards and honors received by Merriam during his long career.
  - Degrees from University of Wyoming and Montana State University, 1962-1963 (Box-folder 37/1)
  - Correspondence Concerning Honorary degree from the University of Wyoming, 1962 (Box-folder 37/2)
  - Correspondence and clippings concerning honorary degree from Montana State University, 1963 (Box-folder 37/3)
  - Award Certificates, 1920-1973 (Box-folder 37/4)
  - Newspaper Clippings-Awards and Honors, 1940-1975 (Box-folder 37/5)
- Scrapbooks and Photo Albums, circa 1900-1939; Series XI; 1 oversize box
  This series includes four bound scrapbooks and photo albums. Most materials are from the early years of Merriam's life and professional career. Volumes include numerous loose materials. Researchers are asked to exhibit particular care in viewing the materials in this series.
  - Scrap Book, University and Rhodes Scholar Program, ca. 1900 -1913; 487(XI):1 (Box 40OS)
  - Photo Album, European Trip, 1904-1906; 487(XI):2 (Box 41OS)
  - Lithographs and oversize certificates, 1925-1939; 487(XI):3 (Box 41OS)
  - Photo Album, Rhodes Scholar Program, WW I, and Reed College, ca. 1904-1920; 487(XI):4 (Box 41OS)
- Photographs, 1914-1975; Series XII; 2.25 linear feet
  This series includes photographs collected throughout Merriam's life but the majority of materials document the activities, gatherings, and publications of the Montana Institute of the Arts. Other photographs can be located in the photo albums and scrapbooks described in Series XI.
  - H. G. Merriam, ca. 1940; 487(XII):1 (Box-folder 38/1)
  - H. G. Merriam, ca. 1930; 487(XII):2 (Box-folder 38/2)
  - H. G. Merriam and Phillip W. Payne, Dec. 1973; 487(XII):3 (Box-folder 38/3)
  - H. G. Merriam and Phillip W. Payne, Dec. 1973; 487(XII):4 (Box-folder 38/4)
  - H. G. Merriam, ca. 1973; 487(XII):5 (Box-folder 38/5)
  - H. G. Merriam, ca. 1973; 487(XII):6 (Box-folder 38/6)
  - H. G. Merriam, ca. 1930; 487(XII):7 (Box-folder 38/7)
  - H. G. Merriam and others, undated; 487(XII):8 (Box-folder 38/8)
  - H. G. Merriam and President Harry Newburn, ca. 1963; 487(XII):9 (Box-folder 38/9)
  - H. G. Merriam and his wife, Fall 1978; 487(XII):10 (Box-folder 38/10)
  - UM Summer School Student Body (S. Rae Logan, back row, 3rd from left-1st summer on staff and W.W. Kemp, 2nd to right), ca. 1914; 487(XII):11 (Box-folder 38/11)
  - R. Fehlberg, undated; 487(XII):12 (Box-folder 38/12)
  - Verne Dusenberry, undated; 487(XII):13 (Box-folder 38/12)
  - Merrill G. Burlingame, undated; 487(XII):14 (Box-folder 38/12)
  - Katherine T. Widmer, Bozeman, undated; 487(XII):15 (Box-folder 38/12)
  - Katerine Guest, MIA, undated; 487(XII):16 (Box-folder 38/12)
  - Gretchen Gellison, MIA, undated; 487(XII):17 (Box-folder 38/12)
  - Mrs. Mackey, undated; 487(XII):18 (Box-folder 38/12)
  - "B.K." at 87th Birthday, Sept. 22, 1975; 487(XII):19 (Box-folder 38/12)
  - Ruth Longworth, undated; 487(XII):20 (Box-folder 38/12)
  - Mrs. Ralph L. Benjamin, Shelby, Montana, undated; 487(XII):21 (Box-folder 38/12)
  - Warren Jennison, Jewel Basin, 1948; 487(XII):22 (Box-folder 38/13)
  - Audrey Bruffey, MIA, undated; 487(XII):23 (Box-folder 38/13)
  - Paul A. Grieder, undated; 487(XII):24 (Box-folder 38/13)
  - Dr. Alfred W. Humphreys, undated; 487(XII):25 (Box-folder 38/13)
  - Elizabeth Lochrie, Butte, undated; 487(XII):26 (Box-folder 38/13)
  - Ray Mattix, MIA, undated; 487(XII):27 (Box-folder 38/13)
  - Robert Taylor, undated; 487(XII):28 (Box-folder 38/13)
  - Maxine Blackmer, undated; 487(XII):29 (Box-folder 38/13)
  - Peggy Sterrett, undated; 487(XII):30 (Box-folder 38/13)
  - L.O. Brockman, undated; 487(XII):31 (Box-folder 38/13)
  - Norman Winstine, undated; 487(XII):32 (Box-folder 38/14)
  - Branson Stevenson, undated; 487(XII):33 (Box-folder 38/15)
  - Gladies Laubui, undated; 487(XII):34 (Box-folder 38/16)
  - Mrs. McDernud, Helena Branch Director, undated; 487(XII):35 (Box-folder 38/17)
  - Al Lucke, undated; 487(XII):36 (Box-folder 38/18)
  - Vermaillae Banta, undated; 487(XII):37 (Box-folder 38/19)
  - Mrs. Mary B. Clapp, undated; 487(XII):38 (Box-folder 38/19)
  - Mrs. Gordon Montgomery, undated; 487(XII):39 (Box-folder 38/19)
  - Robert Athearn, undated; 487(XII):40 (Box-folder 38/19)
  - Robert Athearn, undated; 487(XII):41 (Box-folder 38/19)
  - Mrs. Logan Ostrenn, undated; 487(XII):42 (Box-folder 38/19)
  - Mrs. Milly O. Wells, undated; 487(XII):43 (Box-folder 38/19)
  - Mrs. Henry B. Loventz, Great Falls Branch Director, MIA, undated; 487(XII):44 (Box-folder 38/19)
  - Mrs. Maloney, undated; 487(XII):45 (Box-folder 38/20)
  - Kenneth Burrell, undated; 487(XII):46 (Box-folder 38/20)
  - Mrs. Burrell, undated; 487(XII):47 (Box-folder 38/20)
  - Andy Oja, undated; 487(XII):48 (Box-folder 38/20)
  - Isabel Johnson, undated; 487(XII):49 (Box-folder 38/20)
  - Mr. Maloney, undated; 487(XII):50 (Box-folder 38/20)
  - Mrs. Cook, undated; 487(XII):51 (Box-folder 38/20)
  - McDonald, undated; 487(XII):52 (Box-folder 38/20)
  - Fred Moss, undated; 487(XII):53 (Box-folder 38/20)
  - Mrs. R.K. West, Jr., undated; 487(XII):54 (Box-folder 38/20)
  - Unidentified, undated; 487(XII):55 (Box-folder 38/21)
  - Unidentified woman, undated; 487(XII):56 (Box-folder 38/21)
  - Unidentified woman, undated; 487(XII):57 (Box-folder 38/21)
  - Unidentified man, undated; 487(XII):58 (Box-folder 38/21)
  - Unidentified man, undated; 487(XII):59 (Box-folder 38/21)
  - Unidentified woman, undated; 487(XII):60 (Box-folder 38/21)
  - Unidentified woman, undated; 487(XII):61 (Box-folder 38/21)
  - Unidentified man, undated; 487(XII):62 (Box-folder 38/21)
  - Unidentified, two women, undated; 487(XII):63 (Box-folder 38/21)
  - Orchestra Group, undated; 487(XII):64 (Box-folder 38/22)
  - Female vocalist, undated; 487(XII):65 (Box-folder 38/22)
  - Male pianist, June 1960; 487(XII):66 (Box-folder 38/22)
  - Lewis, composing music, June 1960; 487(XII):67 (Box-folder 38/22)
  - Bruce Kirry, June 1962; 487(XII):68 (Box-folder 38/22)
  - Lewis at pottery wheel, June 1960; 487(XII):69 (Box-folder 38/23)
  - Man at pottery wheel, undated; 487(XII):70 (Box-folder 38/23)
  - Man at pottery wheel, undated; 487(XII):71 (Box-folder 38/23)
  - Man explaining pottery, undated; 487(XII):72 (Box-folder 38/23)
  - Pottery, undated; 487(XII):73 (Box-folder 38/23)
  - Pottery, undated; 487(XII):74 (Box-folder 38/23)
  - People at art exhibit, undated; 487(XII):75 (Box-folder 38/24)
  - People at art exhibit, undated; 487(XII):76 (Box-folder 38/24)
  - People at art exhibit, June 1960; 487(XII):77 (Box-folder 38/24)
  - Man at art exhibit, undated; 487(XII):78 (Box-folder 38/24)
  - Man teaching art, undated; 487(XII):79 (Box-folder 38/24)
  - Man teaching art, undated; 487(XII):80 (Box-folder 38/24)
  - Walt Woodcock, Fine Arts Chairman, Painting by Orlin Helgoe 138, 1959; 487(XII):81 (Box-folder 38/24)
  - People at art exhibit, undated; 487(XII):82 (Box-folder 38/24)
  - Man explaining mosaic, undated; 487(XII):83 (Box-folder 38/25)
  - Man explaining mosaic, undated; 487(XII):84 (Box-folder 38/25)
  - Man explaining mosaic, undated; 487(XII):85 (Box-folder 38/25)
  - People at art show, undated; 487(XII):86 (Box-folder 38/25)
  - People at art show, undated; 487(XII):87 (Box-folder 38/25)
  - Children at art exhibit, undated; 487(XII):88 (Box-folder 38/26)
  - Thomas Jermin of Great Falls, undated; 487(XII):89 (Box-folder 38/27)
  - Branson, printing, undated; 487(XII):90 (Box-folder 38/28)
  - Women discussing art, undated; 487(XII):91 (Box-folder 38/29)
  - Kids performing with others watching from backstage, undated; 487(XII):92 (Box-folder 38/30)
  - Kids performing as Native American dancers, undated; 487(XII):93 (Box-folder 38/31)
  - Women weaving, undated; 487(XII):94 (Box-folder 38/32)
  - Mr. and Mrs. Maloney, Helena, undated; 487(XII):95 (Box-folder 38/33)
  - People at conference/show, undated; 487(XII):96 (Box-folder 38/34)
  - People at conference/show, undated; 487(XII):97 (Box-folder 38/34)
  - People at conference/show, undated; 487(XII):98 (Box-folder 38/34)
  - People at conference, undated; 487(XII):99 (Box-folder 38/35)
  - People at conference, undated; 487(XII):100 (Box-folder 38/35)
  - People at conference, undated; 487(XII):101 (Box-folder 38/35)
  - Harold Ruth (right) with relatives, undated; 487(XII):102 (Box-folder 38/36)
  - Vistor at exhibit, undated; 487(XII):103 (Box-folder 38/37)
  - Man and Woman discussing art, undated; 487(XII):104 (Box-folder 38/38)
  - Art displays, undated; 487(XII):105 (Box-folder 38/39)
  - Art displays, undated; 487(XII):106 (Box-folder 38/39)
  - Art displays, undated; 487(XII):107 (Box-folder 38/39)
  - Art displays, undated; 487(XII):108 (Box-folder 38/39)
  - Art displays, undated; 487(XII):109 (Box-folder 38/39)
  - Art displays, undated; 487(XII):110 (Box-folder 38/39)
  - Art displays, undated; 487(XII):111 (Box-folder 38/39)
  - Art displays, undated; 487(XII):112 (Box-folder 38/40)
  - Art displays, undated; 487(XII):113 (Box-folder 38/40)
  - Art displays, undated; 487(XII):114 (Box-folder 38/40)
  - Art displays, undated; 487(XII):115 (Box-folder 38/40)
  - Art displays, undated; 487(XII):116 (Box-folder 38/40)
  - Pottery, undated; 487(XII):117 (Box-folder 38/41)
  - Ceramic head box by John Murphy, 1968; 487(XII):118 (Box-folder 38/42)
  - Art display, undated; 487(XII):119 (Box-folder 38/43)
  - Art display-painting by Morrison, undated; 487(XII):120 (Box-folder 38/44)
  - Art display, undated; 487(XII):121 (Box-folder 38/45)
  - Ceramics, undated; 487(XII):122 (Box-folder 38/46)
  - Art display, undated; 487(XII):123 (Box-folder 38/47)
  - Art display, undated; 487(XII):124 (Box-folder 38/48)
  - Art display, undated; 487(XII):125 (Box-folder 38/49)
  - Art display, undated; 487(XII):126 (Box-folder 38/50)
  - Paintings, undated; 487(XII):127 (Box-folder 38/51)
  - Paintings by James Der, undated; 487(XII):128 (Box-folder 38/52)
  - Paintings by Branson Strenson, undated; 487(XII):129 (Box-folder 38/53)
  - Painting, undated; 487(XII):130 (Box-folder 38/54)
  - Drawing of Robert Bears and his wife, 1957; 487(XII):131 (Box-folder 38/55)
  - House and Car, undated; 487(XII):132 (Box-folder 38/56)
  - Building, undated; 487(XII):133 (Box-folder 38/57)
  - The five Presidents including H. G. Merriam, undated; 487(XII):134 (Box-folder 38/58)
  - H. G. Merriam and others at MIA function, undated; 487(XII):135 (Box-folder 38/59)
  - H. G. Merriam and group, undated; 487(XII):136 (Box-folder 38/60)
  - H. G. Merriam and Harriette Cashman, Bozeman, Montana, 1952; 487(XII):137 (Box-folder 38/61)
  - H. G. Merriam and others, June 1960; 487(XII):138 (Box-folder 38/62)
  - Group at Picnic, undated; 487(XII):139 (Box-folder 38/63)
  - People talking, undated; 487(XII):140 (Box-folder 38/64)
  - People talking, undated; 487(XII):141 (Box-folder 38/65)
  - Group at picnic, undated; 487(XII):142 (Box-folder 38/66)
  - Group at picnic, undated; 487(XII):143 (Box-folder 38/67)
  - Group at picnic, undated; 487(XII):144 (Box-folder 38/68)
  - Group at picnic, undated; 487(XII):145 (Box-folder 38/69)
  - Group at picnic, undated; 487(XII):146 (Box-folder 38/70)
  - Women at picnic, undated; 487(XII):147 (Box-folder 38/71)
  - At picnic Ken Ralston, Larry Gill, Isabelle Johnson, undated; 487(XII):148 (Box-folder 38/72)
  - At picnic, Bill Stockton, undated; 487(XII):149 (Box-folder 38/73)
  - Laubui and LaDonna getting autograph, undated; 487(XII):150 (Box-folder 38/74)
  - Shope and one of his horses, undated; 487(XII):151 (Box-folder 39/1)
  - Woman speaking, undated; 487(XII):152 (Box-folder 39/2)
  - Group at conference, undated; 487(XII):153 (Box-folder 39/3)
  - Man speaking, undated; 487(XII):154 (Box-folder 39/4)
  - Man speaking, undated; 487(XII):155 (Box-folder 39/5)
  - People at conference, undated; 487(XII):156 (Box-folder 39/6)
  - Man and woman at function, undated; 487(XII):157 (Box-folder 39/7)
  - People talking, undated; 487(XII):158 (Box-folder 39/8)
  - Group at conference, 1960, June; 487(XII):159 (Box-folder 39/9)
  - People talking, 1960, June; 487(XII):160 (Box-folder 39/10)
  - People eating, 1960, June; 487(XII):161 (Box-folder 39/11)
  - Unidentified man, 1960, June; 487(XII):162 (Box-folder 39/12)
  - People talking, 1960, June; 487(XII):163 (Box-folder 39/13)
  - Branson Sterenson and woman (probably wife) from Great Falls, undated; 487(XII):164 (Box-folder 39/14)
  - Man talking, undated; 487(XII):165 (Box-folder 39/15)
  - Men with car, undated; 487(XII):166 (Box-folder 39/16)
  - Mac Lewis and Ben Pursley, Billings branch-exhibit chairman, 1958, December; 487(XII):167 (Box-folder 39/17)
  - Group of people, undated; 487(XII):168 (Box-folder 39/18)
  - Women at craft sale, undated; 487(XII):169 (Box-folder 39/19)
  - Women at craft sale, undated; 487(XII):170 (Box-folder 39/20)
  - People talking, undated; 487(XII):171 (Box-folder 39/21)
  - Group of people, undated; 487(XII):172 (Box-folder 39/22)
  - Photo by Bob Fehlberg, undated; 487(XII):173 (Box-folder 39/23)
  - Spider Web photo by Ernest Bruffey, undated; 487(XII):174 (Box-folder 39/24)
  - Two men standing outside of a building, undated; 487(XII):175 (Box-folder 39/25)
  - Burn, undated; 487(XII):176 (Box-folder 39/26)
  - People among mountains, undated; 487(XII):177 (Box-folder 39/27)
  - "North of the Milk" by Ernest Bruffey, undated; 487(XII):178 (Box-folder 39/28)
  - Unidentified European city from WWI, undated; 487(XII):179 (Box-folder 39/29)
  - MIA festival, 1950; 487(XII):180 (Box-folder 39/30)
  - MIA festival, 1950; 487(XII):181 (Box-folder 39/31)
  - MIA festival, 1950; 487(XII):182 (Box-folder 39/32)
  - MIA festival, 1950; 487(XII):183 (Box-folder 39/33)
  - MIA festival, 1950; 487(XII):184 (Box-folder 39/34)
  - MIA festival, 1950; 487(XII):185 (Box-folder 39/35)
  - MIA festival, 1950; 487(XII):186 (Box-folder 39/36)
  - MIA festival, Pottery wheel, 1950; 487(XII):187 (Box-folder 39/37)
  - Billings Arts Association Christmas showing student Union-EMCE campus, 1957, December; 487(XII):188 (Box-folder 39/38)
  - Billings Arts Association Christmas Showing, 1957, December; 487(XII):189 (Box-folder 39/39)
  - Billings Arts Association Christmas showing, 1957, December; 487(XII):190 (Box-folder 39/40)
  - Billings Arts Association Christmas showing, 1957, December; 487(XII):191 (Box-folder 39/41)
  - Pottery in foreground is stoneware, wheel through and created by Lyndon Pomeroy (and letter from Lyndon Pomeroy with descriptions of 192-200), 487(XII):192 (Box-folder 39/42)
  - Figure group, potter figure, bowl and covered jar by Mae Louis bottles in back by Kay Smith of Butte, unidentified women, undated; 487(XII):193 (Box-folder 39/43)
  - Bob Hendrickson demonstrating gem faceting, undated; 487(XII):194 (Box-folder 39/44)
  - Bob Morrison demonstrating the process of lithography, undated; 487(XII):195 (Box-folder 39/45)